Paalamugan S

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack



Personal details

Name Paalamugan S

Email address developer@paalamugan .com

Phone number +918838782493

Website paalamugan.com

Certificationspaalamugan.com/certifications

LinkedInlinkedin.com/in/paalam
ugan-s-a6baa315b

GitHub github.com/paalamugan

Profile

Having **6+ years** of experience in **Full-Stack development** and more enthusiasm for my work. Extensive experience in working with **Product development** and strong skill sets in both **Front-End** and **Back-End development**.

Skills

Frontend Development - HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, NextJs, React, Redux, Angular, Vue, Svelte, GatsBy, Styled-Components, Chrome Extension.

Backend Development - NodeJs, NestJs, Express, Socket.io, REST API, Graphql, Jest, Mocha, Cypress, Mongodb, Mysql, Redis, Sequelize, Prisma, RabbitMq, PubSub.

Devops Development - Web Security, Security Engineer, Git, Jenkins, CI/CD, GitHub Actions, Hosting, Networking, Google Cloud Platform, Distributed System, Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Docker, Kubernetes, SonarQube, Synk.

Full Stack Development - MERN Stack, MEAN Stack, JAM Stack, NextJS, Remix.

Operating System - Linux(Ubuntu), MacOS, Windows.

Achievements

Own Website Development:

I developed my website from scratch using **NextJS** Framework with **100% covering** all software standard levels.

<u>Click Here</u> to see the screenshot of my website performance from the **chrome developer tool(lighthouse) survey**. **Hard work** and **passion** for coding gave me **good learning** and **encouraged me** to do much better.

If you're interested, You can also check out my website here. https://paalamugan.com

NPM Package:

I Published **3 npm packages** to the **npm registry** to make the **developer's work easy** when they will work using a **single-spa micro frontend** with **React** framework.

- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/react-styleguide
- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/global
- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/config

Employment

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack

Aug 2021 - Present

Quantiphi Analytics Solution, Bangalore

- Working as a Full-Stack Engineer with Angular, Reactjs, Nextjs, and Nodejs Frameworks on top of the Typescript Language.
- Currently I am working with a Maersk client, In this
 project, I have been working on NextJS with TypeScript
 framework, Redux for State management in the Micro
 frontend UI, Nodejs with Express, TypeScript for
 Backend, Prisma for relational database connection, and
 Helmet NPM Package for API Security in the Micro
 service's backend.
- Worked with @testing-library/react, Jest, Mocha, Chai, and Cypress framework for TDD and BDD.
- Had worked with clients such as Arizona Health Care Cost Containment System (AHCCCS), and General Motors-USA
- Worked on React for Arizona Health Care Cost Containment System (AHCCCS) Project.
- Implemented **AHCCCS** Internal Admin UI using **React** with **TypeScript** framework.
- Worked with Angular12, NodeJs, Express, Typescript, and PubSub for General Motors-USA Project.
- Created a **Backend** Server using **Express** with **TypeScript** from scratch as per the client's requirement.
- Developed showing all conversations and session listing UI page in frontend using Angular with TypeScript framework.
- Implemented some of the **Dialogflow Messenger** chatbot functionality that doesn't support by **Dialogflow**.
- I played around with **HTML dom-manipulation** using **Javascript** as per client need.

- Implemented additional functionality like Refresh, Language Switch, and FullScreen buttons in the Dialogflow Messenger chatbot.
- Created custom **webpack** configuration for the minified bundle of all the script files.

Software Engineer

Dec 2018 - Jul 2021

NamLabs Technologies Pvt Ltd, Chennai

- Worked as a Full stack web developer at NamLabs Sass Based Product Company.
- Worked on 4 Products such as Atatus, UI Inspector, ReplayBird, and LeadMine.
- Worked extensively on Typescript, Angular, React, Redux, GatsBy, Vue, Jest, and Mocha Framework in frontend development and NodeJS with Express, Python with Flask in backend development.
- Worked with both Relational(Mysql, Clickhouse) and Non-Relational(Mongodb, Redis, Meilisearch) Databases.
- Developed the application along with the solution design independently from scratch.

Atatus Product:

- Developed full Layout module for atatus documentation page using **Jekyll(Static Site Generator)** tool.
- Implemented 5 main features of atatus product:
 Application Performance Monitoring, Browser
 Monitoring, Logs Monitoring, Infrastructure Monitoring, and Synthetic Monitor.
- Implemented Most of the functionality in the Synthetic monitor feature both Frontend(Angular) and backend (NodeJs). It includes web monitors, DNS monitoring, SSL monitoring, and TCP monitoring.

ReplayBird Product:

 Developed a Full Static website for end-to-end individually using GatsBy(ReactJs and Redux) with Typescript and Graphql Framework.

Lead Mine Product:

 Implemented storing credit/debit card details information powered by Stripe(Payment Tools) and developed a subscription page using Vue Framework with Typescript.

UI Inspector Product:

 Developed Dashboard Page, Testcase Page, and Plan Page in both front end and back end using Angular, MongoDB, and NodeJS with Typescript.

- Done test run in **Cron Server** every 5min, 10min, and 1 hour and put some entry in **Redis** to check the status is passed or failed.
- Build custom **chrome extension** tools to help the user action in the record and save it to **MongoDB**.
- Record the user action with the help of **chrome extension** tools and run the test with a specific plan.

Junior Software Engineer

May 2018 - Nov 2018

Add-on Technology, Chennai

- Worked as a MEAN stack developer where I implemented Bakery internal Product(Anumod Bakery) using MEAN stack technology(MongoDB, Express, Angular, NodeJs).
- Created the bakery application from scratch using Angular
 6 with Typescript on the frontend side, and NODEJS with Typescript, and Express in the backend.
- Implemented a Solution for Sending Messages to the customer about the order detail using **nodemailer**.
- Developed Small E-commerce Project using Reactjs with TypeScript, Redux for State management, and Material-UI framework.
- In the E-Commerce project, I have implemented CRUD API for products list in NodeJS with Express, Typescript, Sequelize(MYSQL) npm Package.

Software Developer

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

Muthu Soft Labs, Chennai

- Worked as a Software developer at Muthu Soft Labs and learned HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, Nodejs, and Photoshop.
- Worked on an internal project called tangedco using Angular and Nodejs Framework.
- Developed UX Design for FinePaperSource Project using Photoshop.

Education

B.E - ECE

Jun 2013 - Apr 2017

P.B College Of Engineering, Chennai

Studied an Electronics and Communication Engineering